gerow@usc.edu; http://www.linkedin.com/in/gerow

http://mgerow.com; 918-740-1775

Professional Summary

A National Merit Scholar Computer Engineering and Computer Science student at USC with over four years of programming experience and nearly a year of experience working in a professional setting including working on internal IT applications and embedded set top box applications. A two year member of the USC Autonomous Underwater Vehicle team competing in the AUVSI RoboSub event.

Education

 University of Southern California—Los Angeles, CA Majoring in Computer Engineering and Computer Science

- University GPA: 3.5, Major GPA: 3.9

- Presidential Scholar

- Projected Graduation Date: May, 2014

Technical Summary

- Languages: C, C++, Java, Go, Python, Verilog, LATEX, Motorola 68000 Assembly
- Libraries/Frameworks: OpenGL, ROS (Robot Operating System), OpenCV, Berkeley Sockets
- Systems/Tools: Linux and Unix variants (Debian, Ubuntu, Solaris), OSX, Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7, SVN, Git, Mercurial, MongoDB, MySQL, Eclipse, Multithreaded Environments (Using Agents)

Professional Experience

• DIRECTV—El Segundo, CA

Software Engineering Intern May 2012-August 2012

- Embedded systems work with set top box UI in Java
- Created tool to increase productivity when working with set top box assets
- Nelson Auto Group—Tulsa, OK

Information Technology Intern May 2011-August 2011, December 2011-January 2012

- Created a system to effectively and efficiently keep copies of all physical media needed for the company's computer and technical systems.
- Created a system to allow managers to easily access recorded calls through a web interface using PHP to access Asterisk servers.

Projects Outside of School

- Projects Created/Forked
 - Boop: Lightweight Go server for running commands in response HTTP actions. Very good for throwing together
 quick solutions when needed. https://github.com/gerow/boop
 - gnome-shell-google-calendar: Fork of script to allow Google Calendar integration into GNOME 3. Added ability to
 use within GNOME 3 under Ubuntu. https://github.com/gerow/gnome-shell-google-calendar
 - btcreg: A service for aliasing bitcoin addresses agains email addresses. Mainly created in order to play around
 with creating database driven web applications using Go and MongoDB. https://github.com/gerow/btcreg
 - This Resume: Yes, even this resume is written in LATEX. https://github.com/gerow/resume

Projects Done With Others

 LittleNote: An iPhone app for sending notes to your significant other. Worked on backend side implemented as a Ruby on Rails application. https://github.com/kcbarry/LittleNoteWeb

• Projects Contributed To

Goose: Database migration tool for Go. Added sqlite3 support. Currently working on support for applications
that wish to target multiple database types. https://bitbucket.org/liamstask/goose

Club Experience

• USC Autonomous Underwater Vehicle Team—Los Angeles, CA

Member of Software Team September 2010–May 2012

- Wrote C++ code for robot running within the ROS environment under Ubuntu.
- Gained experience working with vision processing using OpenCV.